You know our school is an  international school -  it's a Canadian school
ボドウェル高校は、カナディアンスクールであると同時に、さまざまな国から
but full of students from different countries, which is
生徒が集まる、ユニークな、インターナショナル
very unique
スクールです。
Finishing, high school at Bodwell is a very significant milestone
ボドウェル高校を卒業することは、生涯において重要な１つの通過点です。
For our graduates it's much more than finishing their study,
ボドウェルの卒業生にとって、卒業は単に高校課程を終了するだけではなく、
it is finishing an important stage of life.
人生においても大切な時期を終了する事です
Students, who board at the school gain a lot of life experience
寮生は、今後の人生に役立つ、様々な体験をしました。
that we need to stretch our imaginations to understand
その経験は、私たちの想像以上のものです。
Of course they experience a lot of laughter, fun and excitement
勿論、学校・寮内での日々の生活の中
in school and in the residence every day.
沢山笑ったり、楽しい経験もあります
However there are moments of sadness and loneliness
その一方で、悲しい出来事や、ホームシックで、
when some of them miss home,
辛い時期もあったでしょう。
others not used to the new food, the new situations, and the new people.
新しい生活環境、新しい人間関係に慣れなかった事もあったでしょう。
Overall, our graduates achieve a much higher level
でも、今日の卒業生たちは、それらを大きく乗り越え
of self-management, confidence, and maturity
他の同世代の生徒にくらべ、自己管理能力
compared to other students of similar age. I admire them.
自負心をつけ、大きく成長しました。私は、誇りに思います。
I truly do.
心の底からそう思います。
They learn to solve problems and they learn to be independent
彼らは、如才ない問題解決方法を身に着け、自立することを学びました。
It is much more than academic achievement that our graduates should be proud of.
それはある意味、学業結果と同様に価値があり、卒業生たちは誇りに思うべきです
These students, who come, from home they share this diverse and rich
これらの様々なバックグランドを持った生徒達こそが、
socio- cultural environment at Bodwell.
ボドウェルの豊かな多文化コミュニティーを築いています。
I urge you to pay attention to what our graduates say today.
是非、今日の卒業生たちが何を思っているか、耳を傾けて下さい。
What they say about their life  and about their aspirations.
彼らが、どのようにな生活をしてきたか、どのような目標をもっているか
Learning to respect people's
違う文化や信仰をふくめ
people's cultural beliefs and
お互いを尊重することを学び
The way they see the world in from their eyes and their perspective
彼らの視点から、どのように世界が映っているか
Perspective
様々な観点
People and students from all other
色々な違うバックグランド、文化、民族性
backgrounds, cultures,  and ethnicities
をもった生徒達が交じりあい、
that come together and make a community
歩み寄りできたコミュニティー
Community
コミュニティー
The greatest lesson i've learned, while I've been here is to be your open-minded and respectful
ボドウェルで学んだ一番のレッスンは、視野を広げられた事、お互い尊重必要性を学んだ事です。
Patience, tolerance, and just how to be myself around other people
忍耐力、包容力、そして常に自分自身であること。
Cooperation,
協力
Identity
アイデンティティー
Knowing that everyone is equal
人間はだれしも同等であること
Perseverance
根気づよさ
Tolerance
包容力
My leadership skills
リーダーシップスキル
Courage
勇気
Harmony
協調性
To respect other's cultures
他文化の尊重
I learned how to respect their beliefs
私は、様々な信念や信仰を尊重する大切さを学びました。
Respect respect respect
尊重　尊重　尊重
Another lesson i've learned is maturity
他には、精神的に大人になる事を学びました。
Independence is very important for a boarding high school student
寮生にとって、自立性はとても重要です。
I came to Bodwell and I became an independent person
私は、ボドウェルに来たことで、自立した人間になる事ができました。
I see myself impacting, greatly, the lives of young people.
私は、子供の将来に多大な影響を与える存在になりたいと思います。
I see myself running for president in Mexico
私は、メキシコの大統領になりたいと思います。
I want to be someone who helps other people
私は、人を助けることが出来る人間になりたい。
..as a cardiac surgeon saving lives every single day
心臓外科医として、毎日、人の命を救いたいです。
...always wanted to become a pilot
子供のころからパイロットになりたかったです。
Film Editor
映画編集者
I will become a lawyer
私は、弁護士になります。
I want to be an architect when I grow up
私は、将来建築家になりたいです。
A journalist
ジャーナリスト
Surrounded by people I love
愛する人たちに囲まれたいです。
I think the greatest lesson I've learned from my time here
私がボドウェルで学んだ最も重要なことは
No matter where you're from or what language you speak,
出身地や母国語が異なっていたとしても、
we can still all work together to make a better world tomorrow.
私たちが、より良い世界を築き上げるために協力しあえることです。
This environment inspired me a lot.
ボドウェルの環境は、私の見解を広げる為、多くの影響を与えてくれました。
I'm proud of myself.
自分を誇りに思います。